[Subtitles by danielsangeo]
[straining]
Yeah, I can't lift this.
We should've designed this suit to have
pneumatic jacks built into the arms.
Can I climb out of here?
No, it doesn't reach the ceiling.
Maybe I should stop this gas
filling the room, huh?
I'm glad they have a valve here
to stop it; this must happen often.
Oh, this is new.
Yeah, this was sealed;
there was no hatch.
Why would we build a ladder
going up to a grate you can't open?
Is this a dungeon?
Yeah, maybe.
[sneezes]
Like, the ladder is just to
tease the prisoners
to thinking they can see
the sky through the grate,
except it's a trick because
they're still inside a dome.
SCIENTIST: I seem to be
seriously wounded.
Yeah, don't touch me.
SCIENTIST: I don't think I can
last much longer.
Well, this IS a dungeon.
SCIENTIST: STAAH!
What?
Oh, I'm sorry! Were you using that ammo?!
Could've fooled me!
So, those are literally your last words?
Screaming at somebody
not to touch your stuff.
Boy, you lived a fulfilling life, huh?
[strange yowling noise]
Okay...
that's definitely more than one ghost.
What am I looking at?
[Geiger counter ticking]
No!
Hey, you're a witness!
[Geiger counter ticking]
Fuck, this even MORE radioactive.
This is exactly the kind of clicking
[Geiger counter ticking]
I don't want to be hearing.
I don't like performing
[Geiger counter ticking]
Dance of the Geiger Counter.
Hey, uhh...
Oh, okay, you're busy. That's good.
Oh, here we go! Oh, wow!
Perfect!
I could use some popcorn for this!
Might want to fire your gun there...
No?
Okay, that's just me.
This guy is giving a performance!
I respect that.
I should get a good grip in case
his body hits me on the way down.
Ah hah! Someone's spying on me! I knew it!
Or maybe he's motioning for me
to follow him but I'm not going to.
Hey, what the hell?
It was just a zombie making him move
around like it's a giant puppet show.
I don't like the implications of this.
All they've been doing so far is running
into walls and acting angry at the world,
and now they're playing
Punch and Judy with the bodies.
The other was dragging it around
like it was a teddy bear.
I don't know if it's a sign of
growing intelligence or something else.
Well, you don't disappoint!
You don't change a bit!
I can always count on you to be horrible.
Simple and horrible.
[kzzt]
Excuse me?
I... thought I heard someone.
Someone green.
Or, maybe I really have caught a bullet
in the head and I'm hearing colors now.
I don't think synesthesia's contagious but
the sky's the limit when
you've got head trauma.
Anyway, if the zombies are
getting smarter,
I think the next logical step is
for them to steal the soldiers' uniforms
and pretend to be one of them.
They would get shot, but the
soldiers shoot each other anyway.
I estimate the zombies would
have about a 50% success rate
at infiltrating us if they tried that.
The soldiers would look at them
and think they're sick or...
well, I don't know WHAT goes
through their heads.
Ehh...
No, you go first! It's cool. I can wait.
This is NOT a line I'm in a rush
to get through.
It just really doesn't pay to be
in front here.
If I thought I could pull it off,
I would put the zombie in MY suit
and just march him out here.
The military would kill him then say,
"Yep, we got Freeman. Our job's done here."
I'm pretty sure they would buy it.
I mean, look at-- Oh yeah, I almost forgot.
Option 3: the most likely option.
[teleportation sound]
Yah!
People keep interrupting me!
But, yeah, Option 3 is the
military is rock stupid.
Like frightening stupid.
Like crash-planes-into-buildings-bomb-your-
own-troops-and-shoot-half-your-squad stupid.
"Duh... whoops! I killed the
wrong guy again!"
Like maybe the only soldiers
that aren't literally retarded
either have non-combative duty
or else they're overseas.
So, what I'm seeing is all that's left.
This isn't THAT hard.
I mean, c'mon, these
are walking green Tasers.
I don't think I want
to wait on THIS crowd.
See, this is what I mean. That guy was just
walking casually in the center of the room,
exposed.
Did he have headphones on? Have music
playing so loud you can't hear gunshots?
They might sell earbuds like
that. I'm not sure.
Must've been pretty good music since
I'm assuming he had his eyes closed
since there were green bolts of
electricity flying around.
Or maybe that just happened to fit the beat
so that he didn't give it much
conscious thought until it was too late.
Music soothes even the...
spaced-out Marine who forgot he
was in the middle of a warzone, apparently.
Shit, if I could document this,
I could publish this as a research
paper on the way out the door!
Because, that's how I roll.
I lose my job, I have a research
paper before I'm out the building!
No, wait, shit. I'm a fugitive and
I killed a lot of people. I forgot.
So, I guess that guard broke the
door because he was bored.
Where do I go now?
[door buzzes]
C'mon! There has to be a
ventilation shaft here somewhere.
What's this? Is this a security station?
No, this is for mixing music.
Maybe the guard's a DJ on the side.
There HAS to be a shaft.
We have great airflow here.
In all my time at Black Mesa I've never
seen anyone suffocate in their office
or black out because
of carbon dioxide poisoning.
That hasn't been true at all
jobs I've worked at.
Oh, you broke it good, huh?
How did--WAHH!
[vortigaunts charging up]
[vortigaunt bolt]
Oh, so you HERDED them there! You really
ARE a space rancher! That's awesome!
Well, I hate to do this to you,
but I have to put them down.
I need you to step over here.
GUARD: We might live longer if
we work together.
Yeah, c'mon waggle-jaw.
I'll be humane about this... not
that I care about that,
but I do care about quick so our
goals are the same.
Oh, what the hell?
How did I miss that?
Okay, that wasn't supposed to happen
and now I've spooked the animals,
so let's just do this the
traditional way.
Our colleague down in the
dungeon would've wanted this.
Or, maybe he just wanted to be
buried with his shotgun shells,
but what do we care? He's dead.
Now, does this work?
Yep! Here we go! Are you
watching this?
Oh, yeah!
Ho!
Whoa!
Christ...
I got a little carried away there.
I'm glad nothing ricocheted at me.
And now the job gets more complicated.
See, it was better when you were
all packed together.
I mean, c'mon, safety in
numbers, right?
[vortigese]
Exactly.
Eh, I spoke too soon.
Now, are there any more of you here?
Drinking some soda? No?
Well, I have to say I'm impressed.
That guy herded six of them into
this hallway. That takes talent.
I wasn't the only one thinking
outside the box.
Y'know, one of my
regrets about leaving here
is I didn't get to do all the
experiments I wanted.
Like I wanted to slip Rohypnol
into the coffee pot for a few weeks
and observe how that affected
people's work habits.
[scientist screaming]
Waah!
Oh.
You're not real.
Ha ha.
Man, you two aren't dead yet?
Oh, right, I just saved you.
You're welcome.
You can pay me, y'know.
I take cash.
SCIENTIST: Freeman!
SCIENTIST: Who would've thought
you'd still be alive!
Oh, funny man! You're saying that to me!
Well, you ARE cowering in my
presence appropriately
so I guess I can't be too hard on you.
Okay, you get to live.
But I'm going to need you to stand there and
smack yourself in the head repeatedly, alright?
GUARD: Bring it on!
Who's he talking to?
There's no one here.
GUARD: Hey, Gordon.
GUARD: It can't get any worse
than this, can it?
Uh, no. This is the absolute
worst it can get.
I can't imagine anything worse
than what you've seen.
GUARD: You have any idea what's going on?
Oh, my God. You people are all hopeless.
You say that like a bored kid
wanting to know what time lunch is.
I can't help you.
You shouldn't have even
made it this far in life.
You lack basic problem-solving
skills. That's so fundamental.
You need to be in a home.
Okay, good. This doesn't even
have a code so I don't need you.
You're going to die here. I'm sorry.
There's no way
[fzzt]
Shit, something's happening. I
think I'm having flashbacks.
HEADCRABBED SCIENTIST: Is
someone there?
Oh, God....
HEADCRABBED SCIENTIST: I... I
can't see a thing...
Okay, I'll try to get it off.
Shit, did I hit him?
I don't want to think about this.
[houndeye squeals]
Yeah, you're next, you hopping maggot!
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK I WANT YOUR ADVICE?!
Shit... everyone's trying to tell me
what to do; ghost, aliens, people,
they're never going to stop
until they're all dead.
Except the ghost.
OHHH!
MOTHERFUCKER!
YOU'RE IN ON IT, TOO!
AND YOU!
They ambushed me!
They ARE getting more intelligent!
That was an honest-to-God trap!
I think the hopper was just bait!
He lured me in there!
Well, that's one problem solved.
Guess I hit him after all.
[door buzzes]
Oh, come ON!
Shit, maybe he ran in there.
Well, will the guard help me
after what I said?
He may be too stupid to be offended,
but he may not even know the code.
Screw it. I don't want the drama.
I'll take the shaft that looks
like an exposed ribcage.
If I have to wrestle with the
maggot thing in here,
I'm pretty sure I'm going to
remember that the rest of my life.
I mean, I'm going to remember a lot of
this, but some things cut deeper than others.
[thumping, gargantua growling]
Oh... wide load coming through...
everybody back up.
[gargantua roaring]
Uh...
Oh, shit. Looks like the bridge
clearance was too low.
Maybe he'll smash a way out of
here and I can just follow in his wake.
And we have locked blast doors here, too,
because, apparently we
anticipated this sort of thing.
I mean, the ceiling was built
high enough for him.
You could perform a
full trapeze act in this room.
Well, this is pretty convenient, really.
Yeah, why not? I'll give this a try as
soon as the electricity dies down some.
Then I won't be stunned before
dropping down twenty feet.
Chuggachuggachuggachuggachuggachuggachugga
chuggachuggachuggachuggachuggachugga!
Ah, that's better.
But now we have an air vent dragon.
Wait, no, too loud.
FUCK YOU!
I HATE YOU AND I'M GONNA GO KILL
YOUR WHOLE FAMILY NOW!
Y'know, the joke's gonna be on me
if I find out later that these things
actually taste good when cooked
and we're raising them in a few years,
but I just don't see
that--WAAAH!
Oh, lucky...
I should do something...!
SCIENTIST: Get back!
[scientist screaming]
I'm kind of freezing up here!
What am I doing?!
This is good, I think!
No, this isn't working!
Let's do it some more!
C'mon!
God!
GUARD: HEY! AAAAAAH!
Get out of there, moron!
Oh, fuuuck!
THIS IS BULLSHIT!
EVERYTHING I'VE BEEN DOING
UP UNTIL THIS POINT
WAS SO I WOULD NOT BE
IN THIS EXACT SITUATION!
BUT NONE OF IT MATTERS BECAUSE GIANT ALIENS
ARE DETERMINED TO FUCK ME ANY WAY THEY CAN!
WAAAAAAAAAH!
OH, THAT'S IT! NOW, I'M DEAD!
I AM DEAD NOW!
NOBODY'S GONNA KNOW HOW AWESOME I AM!
WHAT THE FUUUUUUUUCK!